<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?mso-infoPathSolution productVersion="14.0.0" PIVersion="1.0.0.0" name="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:infopath:CriticalPathTrainingCourseDetails:-myXSD-2010-05-18T18-37-18" href="file:///C:\Users\andrew\Documents\My%20CPT\Courses\CriticalPathTrainingCourseDetails.xsn" solutionVersion="1.0.0.22" ?><?mso-application progid="InfoPath.Document" versionProgid="InfoPath.Document.2"?><my:courseDetails xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:my="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003/myXSD/2010-05-18T18:37:18" xmlns:xd="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003" xml:lang="en-us"><my:title>The Great SharePoint Adventure 2010 Roadshow</my:title><my:description> 
This 2-day course explores the development opportunities with Microsoft’s most recent release of SharePoint. It is a compressed lecture &amp; demo only format of our popular Great SharePoint Adventure 2010 hands-on, classroom oriented class. This roadshow format is great for those people who are limited in the time they can spend out of the office or are working within a limited budget.

The first day of the roadshow focuses on Microsoft SharePoint Foundation 2010 (SPF2010, formerly known as Windows SharePoint Services or WSS 3.0) where you will learn how to develop fundamental SPF2010 building blocks such as Features, application pages, site pages, master pages, Web Part pages as well as how to customize the ribbon and develop a custom user experience. Microsoft made significant improvements in the ways developers access data in SharePoint both on and off the server. In this course developers will learn how to access data in SharePoint using LINQ for SharePoint when on the server. When connecting to SharePoint from off the server developers will also learn how and when to use the WCF Data Services (aka: OData / REST) and the Client Object Model (.NET, Silverlight and ECMAScript). 

The second day of the class moves on to automating business process with workflow using SharePoint Designer 2010 and Visual Studio 2010 as well as developing with Enterprise Content Management, managed metadata and leverage the SharePoint Search platform to create custom search results pages and program against the search API. In addition, developers will also learn how to read, write and surface data in many ways from external systems using the new Business Connectivity Services (BCS, formerly Business Data Catalog (BDC) in SharePoint Server 2007).

Throughout the course students will not only learn how to create robust SharePoint projects and solutions using the new SharePoint Development Tools in Visual Studio 2010, but they will also learn how to customize and extend these tools. In addition developers will learn about the new Sandbox Solution paradigm and best practices around when and how to create robust solutions in this new way of thinking.</my:description><my:courseCode>RS-GSA2010</my:courseCode><my:prerequisites>Attendees should have professional development experience with Visual Studio, the .NET Framework and ASP.NET as well as familiarity with Microsoft Office products such as Word and Excel. It is also recommended (but not required) that attendees have a background with the previous version of Windows SharePoint Services 3.0 / Office SharePoint Server 2007 and have experience working directly with XML files in Visual Studio 2008.</my:prerequisites><my:modules><my:moduleName>SharePoint Foundation Development</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>1</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>In this module we'll dive into the core development concepts in SharePoint Foundation 2010. Developers will get up to speed on the server-side object model and learn how to debug their solutions using the new Developer Dashboard. In addition students will be introduced to the SharePoint Feature and Solution framework as well as how to leverage the new Feature upgrade improvements added to SharePoint 2010.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>SharePoint Server-Side Object model</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Developer Dashboard</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Feature and Solution Framework</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Upgrading Features and Solutions</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>SharePoint Application, Site, Web Part and Master Pages, Ribbon User Experience.</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>2</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>In this module you will learn how to create custom application pages as well as content pages and the details around customizing pages. In addition this module will also dive into the aspects of customizing the SharePoint user interface for custom branding experiences as well as customizing and extending the SharePoint Ribbon.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Application Pages &amp; Site Pages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Adding Custom Actions for Navigation</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Pages Templates and Customization (Ghosting) </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Master Pages and Branding </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Designing Web Part Pages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Customizing and Extending the SharePoint Ribbon</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>SharePoint Data Access - Server Side</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>3</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>Microsoft invested a considerable amount in SharePoint 2010 on ways to get data out of SharePoint lists. New to SharePoint is LINQ integration. LINQ for SharePoint is used for querying and joining lists as well as creating and updating items. In this module you will learn how to setup LINQ for SharePoint and query lists as well as use the more traditional methods of working with SharePoint data using CAML, SPQuery and SPSiteDataQuery.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>CAML</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>SPQuery &amp; SPSiteDataQuery</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>LINQ Primer</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>LINQ for SharePoint</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>SharePoint Data Access - Client Side</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>4</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>Another big investment area in SharePoint 2010 by Microsoft is the introduction of the client object model. This object model extends to .NET, Silverlight and ECMAScript enabling developers an easier way to work with SharePoint than the included Web services. In this module you will learn how to leverage each of these three client object models as well as how to utilize ASP.NET AJAX in SharePoint projects In addition you will also learn how to use the new WCF Data Services (OData/REST) and Web Services to access SharePoint data from off the server.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Overview of the Client Object Model</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Leveraging the .NET Client Object Model</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Leveraging the Silverlight Client Object Model</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Leveraging the JavaScript / ECMAScript Client Object Model</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>WCF Data Services / OData / REST</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Developing Workflows </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>5</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>In this module you will learn how to create custom workflows for SharePoint 2010 using Visio 2010, SharePoint Designer 2010 and Visual Studio 2010. In addition, you will learn how to incorporate custom forms into your workflow solutions.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>SharePoint Integration with Workflow Foundation</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Starting and Monitoring Workflow Instances</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Reusable Workflow Templates with SharePoint Designer 2010 </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Workflow Templates with Visual Studio 2010 SharePoint Tools</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Incorporating ASP.NET and InfoPath Forms to Workflows</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Business Connectivity Services</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>7</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>Microsoft first introduced the concept of the Business Data Catalog (BDC) in SharePoint 2007 to consume data from external sources. In SharePoint 2010 Microsoft improved on this platform by introducing Business Connectivity Services (BCS). BCS adds the ability to read/write data to external systems as well as expand on the available data sources by adding a new concept: the .NET Assembly Connector. In this module you’ll learn how to consume and interact with external data sources as well as how to create a custom .NET Connector.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Overview and Architecture</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using the BCS Server API</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating External Content Types</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating External Lists</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Leveraging External Data in Office 2010 Clients</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating .NET Assembly Connectors</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Enterprise Content Management </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>6</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>Microsoft’s approach to ECM is to encourage more people to participate in ECM solutions by incorporating ECM techniques in traditional collaboration experiences as well as provide the tools for records managers to manage and analyze the large quantities of content. In this module you will learn about Microsoft’s ECM strategy within SharePoint Server 2010. You will also see how you can leverage SharePoint Server 2010 to create robust content-centric solutions using Web Content Management.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Understanding ECM in SharePoint 2010: Records Management, Document Management &amp; Digital Asset Management</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Managed Metadata &amp; Taxonomies </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>In-Place Records Management</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Document Sets</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Unique Document IDs</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Extending Search </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>8</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>Microsoft invested considerably in search in SharePoint 2010 from the previous release. This module will explore the different capabilities of search in the SharePoint 2010 stack including SharePoint search and FAST Search. In addition you will learn how to customize and extend the search experience.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Understanding the SharePoint 2010 Search Landscape </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Custom Search Web Parts </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Custom Search Refiners </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Custom Search Relevance Rankings </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Customizing the Search Results Experience</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules></my:courseDetails>