<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?mso-infoPathSolution name="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:infopath:Course-Detail-Forms:-myXSD-2010-05-18T18-37-18" solutionVersion="1.0.0.24" PIVersion="1.0.0.0" href="http://intranet.sharepointblackops.com/Courses/Course%20Detail%20Forms/Forms/template.xsn" productVersion="14.0.0.0"?><?mso-application progid="InfoPath.Document" versionProgid="InfoPath.Document.2"?><my:courseDetails xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:my="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003/myXSD/2010-05-18T18:37:18" xmlns:xd="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003" xml:lang="en-US"><my:title>SharePoint Brand Camp for SharePoint 2010</my:title><my:description>SharePoint 2010 Brand Camp is an intensive 4-day course for Web designers and developers that need to learn SharePoint-specific techniques to design Web pages and brand Websites in a SharePoint 2010 environment. You will learn how to override and extend the core CSS rules that give SharePoint 2010 sites their standard look and feel. You will also learn how to design, implement and deploy custom master pages that work equally well in Team Sites and Publishing Sites. The course provides extra coverage of branding topics specific to Publishing sites such as creating a site taxonomy, configuring navigation and designing page layouts. This course motivates the need for adding custom client-side behavior behind pages in SharePoint 2010 sites and demonstrates how to accomplish this by writing JavaScript code and by leveraging the jQuery libraries. The course also includes a lecture on Visual Upgrade where you will be taught how to manage site content and branding projects when migrating from a SharePoint 2007 environment to SharePoint 2010. The final lecture focuses on development techniques and discusses how to use SharePoint project in Visual Studio 2010 to deploy your custom branding files into a solution package to achieve the highest levels of reusability and maintainability across site collections and across SharePoint 2010 farms.</my:description><my:courseCode>SBC2010</my:courseCode><my:prerequisites>Students should have a basic knowledge of HTML and CSS and should have experience in SharePoint working with team sites and publishing portals. It is also recommended (but not required) that students have previous experience with JavaScript programming and a Web design tool such as SharePoint Designer, ColdFusion or Dreamweaver.</my:prerequisites><my:modules><my:moduleName>Introduction to SharePoint Branding </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>1</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This introductory lecture provides an overview for Web designers beginning to work in a SharePoint 2010 environment. There will be a quick review of SharePoint terminology and architecture in which students will be introduced to essential SharePoint design concepts such as site collections, master pages, the Master Page Gallery and the Style Library. The lectures concludes with a discussion which highlights the similarities and differences between Team Sites and Publishing Sites from the perspective of a Web designer who is working on a custom branding project.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>SharePoint Branding Overview</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>SharePoint 2010 Architecture</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Introduction to SharePoint Designer 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Anatomy of a Team Site</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Anatomy of a Publishing Portal</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>CSS Primer for SharePoint Web Designers</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>2</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture begins with a discussion of HTML DOCTYPES used in SharePoint 2010 and provides a quick review session covering the syntax for creating and applying CSS rules. Emphasis is given to using modern CSS styling to layout Web pages with floating div elements and to control scrolling. This lecture discusses how SharePoint 2010 integrates a CSS file named corev4.css to provide a common set of CSS rules behind every page in SharePoint 2010 and teaches you the options you have for providing your own custom CSS rules which override and extend the CSS rules inside corev4.css. The lecture concludes with a discussion of how themes are implemented in SharePoint 2010 and discusses the limitations that prevents themes from providing an effective approach for creating a reusable branding solution.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Why CSS?</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Review of CSS Fundamentals and Syntax </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Tools for discovering CSS class names</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using CSS in SharePoint 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Themes in SharePoint 2010</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Creating a Web Site Design</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>3</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture begins by examining the essential questions must be asked at the start of any SharePoint 2010 branding project such as what will be the target screen resolution and which browsers will be supported and need to be integrated into the testing phase. The lecture will also cover the why and how of creating important design documents such as wireframes and design comps. There will also be a discussion of using slices in a professional design tool such as Adobe Photoshop or Microsoft Expression Design to generate image files that will be used to implement the final Web site design. The lecture concludes with a discussion of how to create an initial page layout using HTML and CSS that meets the requirements of your project.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Project Planning</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating a Wireframe</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Design Comps</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using Slices to Create Web-ready images</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Moving the Design into HTML and CSS</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Customizing Master Pages </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>4</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture begins by reviewing the ASP.NET syntax required to work with master pages and by examining the full list of the 34 placeholders controls defined in the standard master pages such as v4.master. There will be a walkthrough of the standard master page named v4.master from top to bottom in which you will learn about the built-in SharePoint controls that are used to link to CSS files and JavaScript files and to provide essential aspects of the SharePoint user interface such as the three common navigation controls. The lecture concludes with a  demonstration of how to reconfigure the master page for a Team Site and to customize this master page using SharePoint Designer 2010 to create a design with a fixed page width.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>ASP.NET Syntax for Master Pages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>The Master Page Gallery</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Customizing a Master Page using SharePoint Designer 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Walkthrough of the essential controls and placeholders in v4.master</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding the purpose of delegate controls in master pages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Changing and customizing a site's master page with SharePoint Designer 2010</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Creating a Custom Master Page</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>5</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture discusses how to design and implement custom master pages by beginning with a minimal starter master page. You will learn about the essential placeholders and SharePoint controls that must be added to any master page running in a SharePoint 2010 environment and the instructor will demonstrates how to integrate these controls into a custom page design. The lecture also discusses the best practice of placing certain navigation controls inside delegate controls to ensure your custom master pages work equally well in Team sites as well as Publishing sites.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Creating a Starter Master Page for SharePoint 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Adding a Custom Master Page to the Master Page Gallery</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring a Site to use a Custom Master Page</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Implementing and Testing a Design</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Custom Navigation in Master Pages</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Designing a Publishing Site</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>6</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>The lecture focuses on the Web Content Manage (WCM) features offered by Publishing Sites in SharePoint Server 2010. You will learn how Publishing sites provide extended functionality for content authoring, content approval, site branding and overall page design using Publishing page. There will be a discussion about information architecture and designing a taxonomy of sites which makes it easier for users to search for and navigate to the information they need. The lecture will also demonstrate how to leverage the built-in support in Publishing sites for uploading and integrating custom master pages and CSS files and for tuning the navigation settings on a site-by-site basis.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Introduction to Publishing Sites</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Publishing Site Taxonomy</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Adding Pages and Sites</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring a Custom Master Page</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Customizing Navigation</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Designing Page Layouts</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>7</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture steps through the process of designing and implementing page layouts from start to finish. You will learn about the fundamentals of creating site columns and content types and discover how to leverage the useful site columns and content types provided by the Publishing features of SharePoint Server 2010. You will also learn essential techniques in SharePoint Designer 2010 for creating and implementing custom page layouts such as creating field controls by dragging and dropping site columns from the toolbox. This lecture also discusses configuring Publishing sites  to enable and disable the use of specific page layouts and site templates and demonstrates techniques for designing page layouts with Web Part Zones for scenarios where it makes sense to allow users to add Web Parts to Publishing pages.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Page Layouts Overview</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Site Columns and Content Types</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating a new Page Layout with SharePoint Designer 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring Page Layouts and Site Templates</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using Web Part Zones to Enable Adding Web Parts to Publishing Pages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered></my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered></my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Working with XSLT in SharePoint 2010 </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>8</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture takes the practical approach of teaching you what you need to know about XSLT to become proficient with using this technology in a SharePoint 2010 environment. The lecture begins by explaining the basic concepts and syntax required to write and test simple XSL transforms. Next, you will learn about the various places XSLT can be used in SharePoint 2010 and you will discover how to customize the XSLT code used behind the XML Viewer Web Part and the Core Search Results Web Part. The lecture ends with a demonstration of leveraging the productivity of the XSLT List View Web Part together with the visual XSLT designers provided by SharePoint Designer 2010.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>World's Fastest Introduction to XSLT</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Writing and Testing XSLT Code</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Overview of XSLT use in SharePoint 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using Custom XSLT files with the XML Viewer Web Part</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Formatting Search Results using XSLT</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Working with the XSLT List View Web Part</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Working with JavaScript in SharePoint 2010</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>9</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture provides a quick review of the fundamental concepts of JavaScript programming including creating anonymous functions and creating JavaScript objects with object initialization syntax. There will also be a quick primer on using the DOM to access and manipulate elements on an HTML page. The heart of the lecture focuses on the reusable JavaScript libraries that are built-in to the SharePoint 2010 environment including ASP.NET AJAX and the SharePoint 2010 JavaScript Class Libraries. You will learn best practice programming techniques for registering client-side event handlers, executing AJAX requests across the network and using model dialogs to interact with users.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>JavaScript Programming Fundamentals</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Writing JavaScript code behind SharePoint site pages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Programming with the Document Object Model (DOM)</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Leveraging the ASP.NET AJAX Library</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Programming with the SharePoint 2010 JavaScript Class Libraries</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Programming User Interaction with JavaScript and Modal Dialogs</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Integrating jQuery into a SharePoint 2010 Site </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>10</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture introduces the fundamental concepts and programming syntax required to get up and running with jQuery . You will learn how to call the jQuery function with various types of selectors to retrieve wrapped sets of HTML elements so you can manipulate their properties such as their contents, position and their CSS styles. The lecture discusses how to register client-side event handlers the jQuery way focusing techniques that result in less code. The lecture also includes coverage of advanced jQuery topics such as executing AJAX calls across the network and leveraging the jQuery UI library to build custom jQuery themes and to leverage advanced jQuery UI controls such as the Accordion component and the Tabs component. </my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>jQuery Programming Fundamentals</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding jQuery Selectors</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using jQuery to Register Event Handlers</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using jQuery Support for Executing AJAX Requests</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using jQuery UI controls such as the Accordion component and the Tabs component</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Migration and Visual Upgrade</my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>11</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture takes a deep dive into the internals of the Visual Upgrade feature of SharePoint 2010 to provide a solid understanding of what happens when migrated sites run in either of the two supported user interface modes. The lecture begins by discussing the critical aspects of the SharePoint 2007 user interface that are carried forward to SharePoint 2010 so that migrated sites can continue to run using the older 2007 user interface. The lecture also discusses how to migrated sites can be upgraded to use the new user interface mode and goes into detail about exactly what happens behind the scenes when switching from one mode to another. Emphasis in this lecture is given to teaching Web designers and developers what is required when updating SharePoint 2007 branding project and migrating custom content to the SharePoint 2010 environment.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Motivation for Visual Upgrade</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>The Inner Mechanics of Visual Upgrade</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Switching Between UI Version Modes</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Managing the Visual Upgrade Process</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Updating SharePoint 2007 Branding Projects</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Refactoring Custom HTML into v3 Sections and v4 Sections</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules><my:modules><my:moduleName>Deployment using Features and Solution Packages </my:moduleName><my:moduleNumber>12</my:moduleNumber><my:moduleDescription>This lecture takes what you have learned in earlier lectures and shows you how to package your custom branding files in a more reusable fashion using solution packages. More specifically, you will learn how to create custom branding solutions that are reusable, version-able and instantly deployable in any SharePoint 2010 environment. The lecture will demonstrate how to create SharePoint projects in Visual Studio 2010 that include features and template files to deploy custom master pages, CSS files and page layouts within the scope of a target site collection. You will also learn how to add custom C# code to a feature receiver and to program using the SharePoint server-side object model so can create features which automatically configure all the sites within a site collection to use one of your custom master pages upon feature activation.</my:moduleDescription><my:topicCovered>Understanding Features and Solution Packages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Solution Deployment using farm solutions versus sandboxed solutions</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Developing a SharePoint solution using Visual Studio 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating a Custom Branding Solution to Deploy Custom Master Pages and CSS files </my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating a Custom Solution to Deploy Site Columns, Content Types and Page Layouts</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise></my:modules></my:courseDetails>