<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?mso-infoPathSolution name="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:infopath:Course-Detail-Forms:-myXSD-2010-05-18T18-37-18" solutionVersion="1.0.0.24" productVersion="14.0.0.0" PIVersion="1.0.0.0" href="http://intranet.sharepointblackops.com/Courses/Course%20Detail%20Forms/Forms/template.xsn"?>
<?mso-application progid="InfoPath.Document" versionProgid="InfoPath.Document.2"?><my:courseDetails xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:my="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003/myXSD/2010-05-18T18:37:18" xmlns:xd="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003" xml:lang="en-us">
	<my:title>SharePoint 2010 for Site Collection Administrators</my:title>
	<my:description>This course is for those users who have the responsibility to manage and customize SharePoint sites and site collections up. In this course you will learn the differences between SharePoint site collections and sites and how to effectively leverage each one. 

Attendees of this course will also be introduced to SharePoint Features and how to leverage them to provide additional plug-in like functionality to SharePoint sites and site collections. Site collection administrators will also learn how to create and customize content within SharePoint sites using content pages, wiki pages, Web Parts lists and document libraries.

Finally students will learn how to secure sites, lists, libraries and the content within lists and libraries using the permission and security infrastructure in SharePoint. In addition attendees will also learn how to create effectively manage search and leverage the new SharePoint metadata tagging capabilities.

This course is for site collection administrators targets a wide range of users including site administrators, project managers, power users, Web masters and anyone else who will serve in the role of managing sites and site collections.</my:description>
	<my:courseCode>SCA2010</my:courseCode>
	<my:prerequisites>Attendees should have experience using a Web browser and interacting with Web-based systems as well as hands-on experience with SharePoint 2007 or 2010 from an end user perspective. Experience with Microsoft Office (any version) as well as administrative experience with a previous version of SharePoint is a plus, but not required.</my:prerequisites>
	<my:modules>
		<my:moduleName>Overview of Sites and Site Collections</my:moduleName>
		<my:moduleNumber>1</my:moduleNumber>
		<my:moduleDescription>In this module, you will learn to understand the logical architecture of SharePoint 2010 sites.  You will explore the benefits of maintaining sites in a hierarchical site collection and understand Universal Resource Locators (URL's) associated with sites and their content.  After this module you will be able to identify the Site and Site Collection administrative utilities available through the web browser.  You will perform a hands-on lab in which you will navigate an existing Site Collection and view native reports in SharePoint 2010.</my:moduleDescription>
		<my:topicCovered>Logical layout of a site collection (vocabulary)</my:topicCovered>
		<my:topicCovered>Understanding the hierarchy of a site collection: administrator's authority, access to galleries, cascading styles, etc.</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding URL's: What's in the URL path?</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding the Site Settings admin page (Site Administration vs. Site Collection Administration)</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise>
	</my:modules>
<my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Creating Sites and Employing Features</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>2</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>Learn the criteria for creating new sites into existing site collections vs. creating new site collections.  After a tour of the default site templates offered in SharePoint 2010, you will learn how create new sites and site collections from a web browser application.  At the end of this module you will be able to customize sites using master pages, themes, cascading style sheets and Features as well as recover content using the Recycle Bin.  You will also perform a hands-on lab in which you will plan and create Sites then witness the effects of enabling and disabling Features.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>When to create sites vs. site collections</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding the out-of-the-box site templates</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding SharePoint Features: availability, dependency, lifecycle, etc.</my:topicCovered>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding the out-of-the-box Site Features and Site Collection Features</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Activating and Deactivating Features</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Managing the 2-stage Recycle Bin Feature</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise>
								</my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Adding Content Pages to Sites and Working with Web Parts</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>3</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>In this module, you will identify the purpose of pages and Web Parts and tour the default Web Parts that ship with SharePoint 2010.  You will learn to connect Web Parts on a Web Part Page to enhance interactivity as well as target a Web Part to a particular audience.  At the end of this module you will perform a hands-on lab to design a Web Part Page.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding pages, and Web Parts and Web Part Pages</my:topicCovered>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding the out-of-the-box Web Parts</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Connecting two Web Parts on a page</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Targeting a Web Wart to a particular audience</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise>
								</my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Adding Lists and Libraries to Sites</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>4</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>Learn the purpose of lists and libraries and review how metadata can enhance data stored in SharePoint 2010..  After explaining site columns and content types you will learn to design and manage workflows to automate business routines.  Upon completing this module you will be able to define views and expose lists and libraries in web parts as well as perform a hands-on lab in which you create and expose a library.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding lists and libraries</my:topicCovered>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding Site Columns and Content Types</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Designing &amp; managing workflows with SharePoint Designer 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Defining views and exposing lists and libraries via Web Parts</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Managing list &amp; list item permissions</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Taxonomies and metadata</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise>
								</my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Securing a Site Collection</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>5</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>In this  module, you will explore the SharePoint 2010 Security Architecture and take a tour of the default SharePoint groups, permission levels and permissions.  You will learn to design a custom security plan by influencing security inheritance in a site collection.  At the end of this module you will perform a hands-on lab in which you will define and assign custom permissions.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>SharePoint security architecture: vocabulary, inheritance and security trimming</my:topicCovered>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding the out-of-the-box SharePoint groups and permission levels</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Real world security: disallowing inheritance, creating groups, creating permission levels and securing individual items</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise>
								</my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Managing SharePoint Search and Sandbox Solutions</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>6</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>Take a tour of Site Collection search settings and explore the SharePoint enterprise search environment.  You will learn to define managed term sets and keywords.  Upon completing this module you will be able to limit data exposure in Search results.  Additionally, you will perform a hands-on lab in which you will customize SharePoint search for a Site Collection.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding the Site Collection search settings</my:topicCovered>
									<my:topicCovered>Defining managed term sets and keywords (tagging)</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Limiting data exposure in Search results</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Overview of Sandbox Solutions</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Managing &amp; Leveraging Sandbox Solutions</my:topicCovered><my:labExercise></my:labExercise>
								</my:modules></my:courseDetails>