<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?mso-infoPathSolution name="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:infopath:Course-Detail-Forms:-myXSD-2010-05-18T18-37-18" solutionVersion="1.0.0.24" productVersion="14.0.0.0" PIVersion="1.0.0.0" href="http://intranet.sharepointblackops.com/Courses/Course%20Detail%20Forms/Forms/template.xsn"?>
<?mso-application progid="InfoPath.Document" versionProgid="InfoPath.Document.2"?><my:courseDetails xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:my="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003/myXSD/2010-05-18T18:37:18" xmlns:xd="http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/infopath/2003" xml:lang="en-us">
	<my:title>SharePoint 2010 Administrators Survival Camp</my:title>
	<my:description>This intensive 5-day course has been designed to teach experienced IT Professionals the essential skills required in administrating a SharePoint 2010 environment. You will quickly learn to install SharePoint Server 2010 and to create a new farm, Web applications and site collections and sites. The course explains SharePoint farm topologies and discusses strategies for scaling a farm by adding Web servers and application servers.
SharePoint Foundation introduces a new service application architecture which replaces the older SharePoint 2007 architecture for Shared Service Providers (SSPs). The course teaches you how to create and configure service applications so they provide access to share resources across Web applications and across farms. You learn how to configure services applications in a new farm using the new Farm Wizard. The course also make a point of teaching you how to create and configure SharePoint 2010 service applications by hand because you will frequently encounter scenarios in production environments where using the Farm Wizard is not appropriate.
The course covers new SharePoint 2010 security enhancements and introduces you to the concepts and terms associated with claims-based security. You will learn how to configure a Web application to support Windows authentication, claims-based authentication, forms-based authentication, anonymous access and SSL.
SharePoint farm administrators are often faced with critical decisions about how to manage large amounts of content across sites, site collections and content databases. The course covers capacity planning considerations and discusses using governance to control the use and growth of the content. Along the way you will learn about other critical SharePoint 2010 administration skills including scripting with Windows PowerShell, upgrading from SharePoint 2007, recovering lost content and planning for disaster recovery.  
The real power of SharePoint 2010 lies within the service applications included with SharePoint Server 2010. The course covers how to configure the SharePoint Server Search Service to facilitate searching through SharePoint site content as well as external content. You will also learn to take full advantage of SharePoint 2010 by configuring other service applications including the Managed Metadata Services, the Business Data Connectivity Service, the Secure Store Service and the User Profile Service.
The course focuses on best practice technique of using features and solution packages to deploy site customizations and custom business solutions. You will learn how to deploy and manage solution packages at the farm-level. The courses then introduces you to the new sandboxing architecture in SharePoint Foundation and discusses how sandboxed solutions provide a more reliable way to run custom code within a production environment. You will learn how to configure the Sandboxed Code Service and how to monitor sandboxed solutions running within your farm.
The course can be used to prepare students for the following Microsoft Certification Exams 70-667: TS: Microsoft SharePoint 2010, Configuring and 70-668: PRO Microsoft SharePoint 2010, Administrator. </my:description>
	<my:courseCode>SSC2010</my:courseCode>
	<my:prerequisites>Attendees should have experience working as an IT professional in a Windows network environment and be familiar with installing and configuring Windows Server 2008, Active Directory and SQL Server. It is recommended (but not required) that attendees have user-level experience with SharePoint 2010 or a previous version.</my:prerequisites>
	<my:modules>
		<my:moduleName>Getting Started with SharePoint 2010</my:moduleName>
		<my:moduleNumber>1</my:moduleNumber>
		<my:moduleDescription>This introductory module introduces students to the fundamental terminology and architecture of SharePoint Foundation and describes the new platform enhancements with the greatest impact on SharePoint administrators. The module also examines the different editions available for SharePoint Server 2010. The module concludes with a discussion of hardware and software requirements and using virtualization techniques to build testing and production environments.</my:moduleDescription>
		<my:topicCovered>SharePoint Foundation Architecture and Terminology</my:topicCovered>
	<my:topicCovered>SharePoint 2010 Enhancements Targeting Administrators</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>SharePoint Server 2010 Editions</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Hardware and Software Requirements</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Virtualization Considerations</my:topicCovered></my:modules>
<my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Installing SharePoint Server 2010</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>2</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module explores the various topologies that can be used to build a SharePoint 2010 farm and introduces the new Service Application architecture of SharePoint Foundation. Students will learn how to choose between common deployment topologies when installing SharePoint Server 2010 in a variety of scenarios. The module also discusses best practice techniques for creating dedicated service accounts in Active Directory to provide the identity for various worker processes in a SharePoint 2010 farm.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Understanding Farm Topologies</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Service Application Architecture</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Dedicated Service Accounts in Active Directory</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Installing SharePoint Server 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating the Farm and the Configuration Database</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Configuring SharePoint Server 2010</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>3</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>The module explores the Central Administration Web Site and discusses how to configure SharePoint Server 2010 after initially creating a new farm. You will learn how to leverage Managed Service accounts and how to configure and schedule timer jobs . The module discusses when to use and when to not to use the Farm Configuration Wizard. The lecture and lab will show you how to create new service application instances by hand for scenarios where using the Farm Configuration Wizard is not appropriate.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Getting Around in Central Administration</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Managed Service Accounts</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Managing Timer Jobs</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using the Farm Configuration Wizard</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring Service Applications by Hand</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Configuring and Administrating Security in SharePoint 2010</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>4</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module examines the different styles of authentication supported in SharePoint 2010 and introduces terms and concepts of claim-based security. You will learn how to install certificates and configure SSL as well as how to configure Windows authentication, Claims-based authentication and forms-based authentication.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Windows Authentication</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Claims-based Authentication</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Forms-based Authentication</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Intranet/Extranet/Intranet Considerations</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring Certificates and SSL</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Creating and Configuring Web Applications</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>5</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module discusses the techniques required to create and manage Web Applications. You will learn to configure Web Applications with host headers and alternate access mappings. The module also explains how to control resource usage within a Web Application by creating quotas and adjusting the new SharePoint Foundation thresholds for list throttling. The lecture will conclude with a discussion of configuring a Web Application to allow for anonymous access.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Configuring DNS and Host Headers</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Creating New Web Applications</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring Alternate Access Mappings</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>List Throttling and Quotas</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring Anonymous Access</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Writing Administrative Scripts using Windows PowerShell</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>6</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>The lecture introduces students to the new world of Windows PowerShell scripting. You will learn how to call cmdlets and use pipelining from the interactive console windows. You will also learn how to write, test and debug Windows PowerShell scripts using the  Windows PowerShell Integrated Scripting Environment (ISE). Finally, you will learn how to load the SharePoint PowerShell snap-in and call cmdlets provided by SharePoint 2010.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Introduction to Windows PowerShell</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Windows PowerShell Console Window</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Writing Windows PowerShell Scripts</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Loading the SharePoint PowerShell Snap-in</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Writing Administrative Scripts for SharePoint 2010</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Managing Site Collection Growth using a Governance Plan</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>7</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module explains how SharePoint sites are provisioned with respect to site collections, Web Applications and content databases. You will see how to create new sites using site templates included with SharePoint Foundation and SharePoint Server 2010 including Team site, Publishing site and Enterprise Wiki. The module discusses customizing sites through the browser by adding site elements such as pages, Web Parts, lists and content types. There will also be a discussion of site customization using the SharePoint Designer 2010 and configuring SharePoint Designer Settings to restrict SharePoint Designer access. The module concludes with a discussion of governance and capacity planning to manage the growth of content across site collections and content databases.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Sites and Site Collections</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Site Templates in SharePoint 2010</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Customizing Sites using the Browser</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Customizing Sites with SharePoint Designer</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Enforcing Governance in Production Environments</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Upgrading Farms from SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2010</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>8</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module focuses on what is required to upgrade SharePoint 2007 farms to SharePoint 2010. You will learn the difference between an in-place upgrade and database attach upgrade as well as the technique for running a hybrid approach. The module also introduces the concepts and mechanisms involved with the Visual Upgrade feature which allows users to begin accessing a SharePoint 2010 site using the older SharePoint 2007 user interface and then to migrate the new SharePoint 2010 user interface.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Preparing a SharePoint 2007 Farm</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>In-Place Upgrade</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Database Attach Upgrade</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using a Hybrid Upgrade Approach</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding Visual Upgrade</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Configuring Search in SharePoint Server 2010</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>9</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module provides an overview of SharePoint 2010 search capabilities and discusses what search functionality is available under various SKUs. The instructor will compares and contrasts SharePoint Search architecture with the architecture of FAST Search. You will also learn how to configure the Search Service Application and to create custom search pages within a site using the Search Web Parts included with SharePoint Server 2010.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Overview of Search in SharePoint 2010</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>SharePoint Search Architecture versus FAST Search</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring the Search Service Application</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Search Pages using the Search Web Parts</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Using Custom Ranking Models</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Configuring the Managed Metadata Service</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>10</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module introduces the architecture and capabilities of the Managed Metadata Service. You will see how to create and collaborate on hierarchical term sets in order to create taxonomies for tagging items and documents. There will be a discussion of creating Enterprise Content Types and configuring a synchronization hub to propagate to sites across one or more farms.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Overview of the Managed Metadata Service</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Creating and Collaborating on Managed Terms Sets</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating Taxonomies using Hierarchical Term Sets</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Tagging Items and Documents</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating a Synchronization Hub for Enterprise Content Types </my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Working with The Business Data Connectivity Service</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>11</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>The module describes the basic architecture of the Business Data Connectivity Service and explains how to create External Content Types to gain read-write access to backend data sources such as databases and Web Services. You how to expose data from connections using external lists. You will learn to configure connections using the Secure Store Service as well as how surface data from a connection using an external list. The module will also include a discussion of generating profile pages within a SharePoint site to create user interface components for entities that live in external data sources. </my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Introduction to the BCS</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Creating External Content Types</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Configuring Security with the Secure Store Service</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Provisioning Profile Pages</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Creating External lists</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Configuring the User Profile Service</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>12</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module discusses how to take advantage of the new Social Networking features in SharePoint Server 2010. You will learn how to set up the User Profile Service Application and to synchronize user profiles against Active Directory user accounts. The module discusses several other topics which rely on user profiles such as notes and tagging, audience targeting and  MySites.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Overview of User Profiles and Social Networking</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Configuring the User Profile Service</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Importing User Profiles from Active Directory</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Notes and Tagging</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Working with My Sites</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Deploying and Monitoring Custom Solutions</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>13</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This modules focuses on best practice technique of using features and solution packages to deploy site customizations and custom business solutions. First, you will learn how to deploy and manage a solution package as a farm-level solution. The module then introduces you to the new sandboxing architecture in SharePoint Foundation and discusses how sandboxed solutions provide a more reliable way to run custom code within a production environment. You will learn how to configure the Sandboxed Code Service and how to monitor sandboxed solutions running within your farm.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Solution Packages and Best Practice Deployment</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Deploying and Managing Farm Solutions</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Sandboxed Solutions Architecture</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Uploading and Activating Sandboxed Solutions</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Monitoring and Administrating Sandboxed Solutions</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Planning for Backup, Restore and Disaster Recovery</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>14</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module covers several different strategies for backing up and restoring content. The discussion begins with versioning and the Recycle Bin. Then you will learn to back up and restore site collections using Windows PowerShell scripts and by hand through Central Administration. The modules conclude with a discussion of how to prepare for disaster recovery so that you can restore a farm in the event of catastrophic server failure.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>Versioning and Restoring Documents</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>Configuring Recycle Bin Behavior</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Site-Level Backup and Restore</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Preparing for Disaster Recovery</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Recovering the Farm After Server Failure</my:topicCovered></my:modules><my:modules>
									<my:moduleName>Health Monitoring and Optimization</my:moduleName>
									<my:moduleNumber>15</my:moduleNumber>
									<my:moduleDescription>This module explores common techniques used to monitor SharePoint 2010 farms and to optimize their performance. You will learn how to troubleshoot problems using the Developer Dashboard and how to read diagnostic information from ULS logs and the Logging Database. The module also discusses using the new Health Analyzer and configuring Usage Reporting.</my:moduleDescription>
									<my:topicCovered>The Developer Dashboard</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Understanding ULS Logs</my:topicCovered>
								<my:topicCovered>The Logging Database</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Health Analyzer and Usage Reporting</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered>Timer Jobs ad Server Affinity</my:topicCovered><my:topicCovered></my:topicCovered></my:modules></my:courseDetails>